<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Matt&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://msarmi9.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Matt&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2021</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 16:03:23 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://msarmi9.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Making Sense of Attention</title>
      <link>https://msarmi9.github.io/posts/attention/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 16:03:23 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msarmi9.github.io/posts/attention/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to deep learning, few ideas have brought about such a radical shift in thinking as attention. Attention changed everything. Like other landmark ideas before it, attention draws merit from simplicity. If that reads like a typo to you, you&amp;rsquo;re not alone. In this post we&amp;rsquo;ll motivate attention as a natural way of looking at sequences and dig into three of the most common attention mechanisms you&amp;rsquo;ll encounter in the wild.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Async Rust: Futures, Tasks, Wakers—Oh My!</title>
      <link>https://msarmi9.github.io/posts/async-rust/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 16:03:23 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msarmi9.github.io/posts/async-rust/</guid>
      <description>Async is all the rage. Python, Rust, Go. Pick your language and chances are it&amp;rsquo;s got some form of async / await going. If you&amp;rsquo;ve never worked with async / await before this can all be somewhat confusing, to put it mildly. In this post we&amp;rsquo;ll take a high level overview of asynchronous programming in general before making our way to Rust, where we&amp;rsquo;ll look at the current state of async&amp;mdash;what it is, how to do it, and how it all works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neural Nets Aren&#39;t Black Boxes</title>
      <link>https://msarmi9.github.io/posts/neural-nets-are-not-black-boxes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 16:03:23 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msarmi9.github.io/posts/neural-nets-are-not-black-boxes/</guid>
      <description>If you think neural nets are black boxes, you&amp;rsquo;re certainly not alone. While they may not be as interpretable as something like a random forest (at least not yet), we can still understand how they process data to arrive at their predictions. In this post we&amp;rsquo;ll do just that as we build our own network from scratch, starting with logistic regression.
This post is very much inspired by this fantastic post by Sylvain Gugger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons from my 0th Year as a Data Scientist</title>
      <link>https://msarmi9.github.io/posts/lessons-from-my-zeroth-year-as-a-data-scientist/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 16:03:23 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msarmi9.github.io/posts/lessons-from-my-zeroth-year-as-a-data-scientist/</guid>
      <description>Later this week, I’ll graduate from the Masters in Data Science Program at the University of San Francisco alongside an incredible cohort of colleagues. It’s been a doozy of a year, to say the least. Now that it’s coming to an end, I’d like to reflect on some of the things I’ve learned and share them with you, in the hope that it’ll be useful to somebody somewhere who, like myself a year ago, is just starting out on their own data journey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker for Deep Learning on AWS</title>
      <link>https://msarmi9.github.io/posts/docker-for-deep-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 16:03:23 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msarmi9.github.io/posts/docker-for-deep-learning/</guid>
      <description>This post will help you set up a GPU enabled Docker container on an AWS EC2 instance. We’ll also cover how to access a Jupyter server running inside the container from your local machine.
Why? One of my favourite things about Docker is that it allows you to easily reproduce your local development environment on a remote machine. This comes in real handy whenever you need to train a model on a GPU.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://msarmi9.github.io/books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msarmi9.github.io/books/</guid>
      <description>Books 📚 Python Architecture Patterns with Python
Fluent Python, 2nd Edition
High Performance Python, 2nd Edition
Rust Programming Rust, 2nd Edition
Refactoring to Rust
Rust In Action
The Rust Programming Language, 2018 Edition
Swift Advanced Swift
Swift In Depth
Deep Learning Deep Learning for Coders with fastai &amp;amp; PyTorch
Deep Learning for Vision Systems
Deep Learning Patterns and Practices
GANs In Action
Generative Deep Learning
Inside Deep Learning
Transfer Learning for NLP</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
